<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Blog EN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 13:54:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 tips for Price Comparison Sites</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-5-tips-for-price-comparison-sites/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-5-tips-for-price-comparison-sites/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 13:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Deborah Penna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17793</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Price comparison sites are becoming increasingly popular among consumers and are an excellent way to advertise your online store and, at the same time, reach a higher percentage of qualified buyers. The savvy internet shopper is more inclined to use &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-5-tips-for-price-comparison-sites/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Price comparison sites are becoming increasingly popular among consumers and are an excellent way to advertise your online store and, at the same time, reach a higher percentage of qualified buyers.</p>
<p>The savvy internet shopper is more inclined to use price comparison sites, when trying to find the best deal, as these sites allow buyers to easily compare products and prices. Let’s review how price comparison sites can help your business.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17799" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Price_tag.EN_.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="238" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17793"></span></p>
<p><strong>1.Maximize your advertising budget</strong><br />
Shopping comparison sites offer a clear advantage: they provide access to a highly qualified audience. As stated by<a href="http://www.allbusiness.com/marketing/advertising-internet-advertising/3913-1.html" target="_blank"> Allbusiness.com</a>, <strong>‘62% of comparison-site shoppers are very likely to make a purchase and spend 25% more than other online consumers.’</strong></p>
<p>Therefore, if you wish to use your <strong>cost-per-click (CPC)</strong> or <strong>pay-per-click (PPC)</strong> budget more effectively, start targeting price comparison sites. They generally offer a lower CPC rate and help you increase conversion rates &#8211; as potential buyers who click on your link are already familiar with your product offering.</p>
<p><strong>2.Improve your ranking on search engines</strong><br />
Listing your products on popular price comparison sites can improve your SEO efforts and, therefore, help your business rank higher in search results.</p>
<p><strong>3.Know your competition</strong><br />
Price comparison engines not only facilitate shopping and product comparison for consumers. They can also help you gain some useful insight on what your competition is doing: which products or services they offer, their pricing level, promotions and much more.</p>
<p><strong>4.Customers reviews</strong><br />
Customer reviews are an excellent way to find out which products and services are highly rated, how your competition is performing, how you compare and how you can improve your services. Most price comparison sites display users’ reviews and feedback.</p>
<p>If you wish to know more about this topic, please read <a href="http://www.marketingdonut.co.uk/marketing/marketing-strategy/pricing/what-can-businesses-learn-from-price-comparison-sites-" target="_blank">‘What can businesses learn from price comparison sites?’</a></p>
<p><strong>5.Price comparison websites</strong><br />
To give you a head start, here’s a list of the major price comparison engines:</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.kelkoo.co.uk/" target="_blank">Kelkoo</a><br />
- <a href="http://www.shopzilla.co.uk/" target="_blank">ShopZillla</a><br />
- <a href="https://www.google.com/shopping" target="_blank">Google Shopping</a><br />
- <a href="https://www.google.com/shopping" target="_blank">PriceGrabber</a><br />
- <a href="http://fr.shopping.com/?sb=1&amp;ncrd=1&amp;rpu=1" target="_blank">Shopping.com</a></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17796 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/ShoppingFeed2222.png" alt="" width="516" height="489" /></p>
<p>The graph below, created by <a href="http://cpcstrategy.com/comparison-shopping/q1-2014/" target="_blank">CPC Strategy</a>, shows the best shopping comparison websites, in terms of conversation rates.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17795 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/CPC-GRAPH.png" alt="" width="452" height="452" /></p>
<h2>Shopping Feed &#8211; your centralised feed management system</h2>
<p>Distribute your products easily on all major price comparison engines and centrally manage all your listings thanks to Shopping Feed.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17794 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Shopping-Feed-Logo-1.png" alt="" width="497" height="110" /></p>
<p>Shopping Feed’s solution will allow you to:</p>
<p>- List your products on shopping comparison sites and e-marketplaces<br />
- Distribute your products via Facebook<br />
- Create PPC campaigns for every product you sell<br />
- And various innovative services such as Buylined, which lets you track the user flow, both on your website and externally.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/comparison-shopping-prestashop/4184-shopping-feed.html" target="_blank">Shopping Feed module</a> is available native in the software or it can be downloaded for free, on PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace. And it is compatible with PrestaShop v1.4 &#8211; v1.6.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-5-tips-for-price-comparison-sites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Types of Reviews that will Make or Break your Business: Are you handling them right?</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-types-of-reviews-that-will-make-or-break-your-business-are-you-handling-them-right/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-types-of-reviews-that-will-make-or-break-your-business-are-you-handling-them-right/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 14:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Benjamin Utterback</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17748</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[  Guest Article by Talia Shani, Author at Yotpo   &#8220;Delete, delete delete!&#8221; That&#8217;s how most of us respond to negative reviews on our stores. But is there a better way? We’ve all been there: One day you open an &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-types-of-reviews-that-will-make-or-break-your-business-are-you-handling-them-right/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<address dir="ltr"> </address>
<address dir="ltr">Guest Article by <a href="http://blog.yotpo.com/author/talia-shani/" target="_blank">Talia Shani</a>, Author at <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/marketing-visibility/yotpo-social-reviews" target="_blank">Yotpo</a></address>
<address dir="ltr"> </address>
<h5 dir="ltr">&#8220;Delete, delete delete!&#8221; That&#8217;s how most of us respond to negative reviews on our stores. But is there a better way?</h5>
<p><a style="font-style: normal; line-height: 24.375px; text-decoration: underline;" href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Top-Image.png"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-17751" style="border-color: #bbbbbb; margin-top: 0.4em; background: #eeeeee;" title="Top Image" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Top-Image.png" alt="" width="640" height="240" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">We’ve all been there: One day you open an inbox to find an email from your reviews solution saying “You have a new review!” You’re excited to see what another one of your happy shoppers has to say, only to open the email and see this particular shopper was&#8230;less-than-happy. You panic, thinking, “Oh no! What do I do?!” And start logging into your reviews moderation page, your mouse hovering over the “Delete” button&#8211;but is that really the best way to handle it? Read on to find out Yotpo’s best practices for handling all different types of reviews.<span id="more-17748"></span></p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Glowing</h2>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-17766" style="margin: auto; display: block; margin-left: 15px;" title="Yotpo Review" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Image-2.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" align="right" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">People who leave truly glowing reviews have helped you out by letting the world know how much they love your store and products, but don’t let it stop there. When you spot a potential evangelist, take the opportunity to develop a relationship with them. A customer who is enthusiastic and vocal can be one of the strongest marketing tools in your arsenal; Even if you have the best marketing copy in the world, <a href="https://econsultancy.com/blog/9366-ecommerce-consumer-reviews-why-you-need-them-and-how-to-use-them" target="_blank">shoppers are 12 times more likely to trust a review over your description of a product</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Pro Tip: When you get a glowing review, approach the reviewer privately and ask if you can use their review elsewhere on your site and in your marketing materials. For example, include snippets from glowing reviews on your check-out page or in an e-mail campaign.</p>
<h3 dir="ltr">Good</h3>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-17757" style="margin: auto; display: block; margin-left: 15px;" title="Image 1" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Image-1.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" align="right" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">When you get a positive review, it’s best to respond to it publicly. Try to respond to as many positive reviews as you can, it shows your current and past shoppers that you really value and appreciate their feedback, making them more likely to leave it. A quick thanks will do, but a personal response is even better.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Pro Tip: If you’re responding to a lot of reviews, you may be tempted to use a boilerplate answer&#8211;don’t do it! Try to vary your responses and make them as personal as possible; include the reviewers name and try to respond to a specific aspect of the review. For example, don’t say “Thanks for the awesome review!” say “Thanks for the awesome review, Carol! We’re so happy to hear you like the fit of your new shirt&#8211;enjoy!”</p>
<h3 dir="ltr">Inaccurate</h3>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-17771" style="margin: auto; display: block; margin-left: 15px;" title="Image 4" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Image-4.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" align="right" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">Although “the customer is always right,” sometimes they just get it wrong. We’ve all seen this type of review; whether positive or negative, it’s filled information that just isn’t true.  If the review is blatantly wrong and could be considered misleading to new shoppers.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Pro Tip: Reach out to these reviewers privately to try and suss out why they included inaccurate info in their review. At best, they’ll see they were wrong and post a new review. At worst, you’ll simply have to hear from an angry customer.</p>
<h3 dir="ltr">Negative</h3>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-17769" style="margin: auto; display: block; margin-left: 15px;" title="Image 3" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Image-3.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" align="right" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">Negative reviews scare a lot of store owners, but they are actually a blessing in disguise. Assuming something actually went wrong, an error on your end should be seen as an opportunity to amaze your shoppers with excellent customer service. <a href="https://www.helpscout.net/blog/customer-complaints/" target="_blank">Studies show that 90% of customers will give you a second chance if you resolve their issue in a timely manner.</a> At Yotpo, we always recommend you go ahead and post negative reviews because it lends credibility to the rest of the good reviews and also helps customers get a real feel for the product.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Pro Tip: Don’t just resolve a customer’s problem, go above and beyond and you’ll have a customer for life. There’s lots of ways to wow them with great customer service&#8211;simply taking the time to get on the phone with them to apologize for a mistake can go a long way. If it’s possible, you might consider giving them a small gift from your store</p>
<p dir="ltr">Now that you know the best way to handle all of these types of reviews, have you been doing it right?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Any other tips for best practices when handling happy or angry shoppers? Let us know below!</p>
<div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-types-of-reviews-that-will-make-or-break-your-business-are-you-handling-them-right/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEO Expert Series &#124; Rand Fishkin of Moz</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/seo-expert-series-rand-fishkin-of-moz/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/seo-expert-series-rand-fishkin-of-moz/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 14:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Benjamin Utterback</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17656</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Enter Rand Fishkin, world renowned SEO expert and co-author/co-founder of the Art of SEO, Inbound.org, and Moz. Rand’s an addict of all things content, search, &#38; social on the web. He teamed up with PrestaShop Moderator, Lesley Paone of dh42 to give you expert &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/seo-expert-series-rand-fishkin-of-moz/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Enter Rand Fishkin, world renowned SEO expert and co-author/co-founder of the <a href="http://www.artofseobook.com/" target="_blank">Art of SEO</a>, <a href="http://inbound.org/">Inbound.org</a>, and <a href="http://www.moz.com" target="_blank">Moz</a>. Rand’s an addict of all things content, search, &amp; social on the web. He teamed up with PrestaShop Moderator, <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/forums/user/435599-dh42/">Lesley Paone</a> of <a href="http://dh42.com/">dh42</a> to give you expert insights into how SEO, PrestaShop and ecommerce work together.<br />
<a href="http://moz.com/about/team/randfish"></p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-17667" style="margin: auto; display: block; margin-left: 15px;" title="Rand Fishkin" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Rand-300x300.jpg" alt="Rand Fishkin SEO PrestaShop" width="300" height="300" align="right" /></a></p>
<ol>
<li>
<h4>What would be your first steps in starting SEO for a newly launched e-commerce site?</h4>
<p>I would first want to think about my overall marketing and unique value proposition. The days when SEO could be achieved by a business or website without something unique that made them truly stand out to the web are over. Today, if you want to perform well in search rankings over the long haul, you need to be remarkable in a way that makes those who see your shop want to share, write about you, and recommend you to others. Establishing that true uniqueness is incredibly challenging, but with billions of people performing billions of searches and only a few top ranking positions for any given set of keywords, competition is naturally going to be intense.</li>
<p><span id="more-17656"></span></p>
<li>
<h4>Do you think every e-commerce site needs a blog?</h4>
<p>No, certainly not. Unless your passion is writing and you can create a remarkable blog that people will want to read and share, I&#8217;d do something else. Find that area of contribution to your site (and your business) where your skills can shine and you can be better than 99% of your competitors and do that. It could be photography or design or video or interactive elements. Perhaps it&#8217;s in-depth guides or how-tos. Maybe you can produce animations or illustrations that perfectly capture your products&#8217; value. Blogs are a popular way to share content, but not every piece of content that you might be uniquely good at is best suited to a blog.</li>
<li>
<h4>What do you think are the most important factors in getting product pages to rank high in search engines.</h4>
<p>&#8212; A powerful domain that many people are linking to and using<br />
&#8212;Individual pages that have lots of editorially-given links and usage data associated with them<br />
&#8212;Keyword targeting that matches what the searcher has typed in<br />
&#8212; A page experience that not only fulfills the searcher&#8217;s needs, but goes beyond utility to provide enjoyment, surprise, and delight as well (this is what the few stores that are able to outrank giants like Amazon have been able to do)<br />
&#8212;A bot-friendly internal link/crawl structure and URL system &#8211; every unique item/category/piece of content has only a single, static, readable, canonical URL<br />
&#8212;Schema markup is a good way to stand out in the SERPs &#8211; there are a <a href="http://searchengineland.com/e-commerce-seo-using-schema-org-just-got-a-lot-more-granular-139236" target="_blank">ton of options listed here</a>.</li>
<li>
<h4>Do you have any suggestions for drop shippers that use a product feed with no unique descriptions?</h4>
<p>If you offer no unique value beyond the availability of the same product many others are offering, you don&#8217;t deserve to rank well. Historically, you could be in an undeserving position and still leverage SEO to rank, but those days are over. My suggestion would be not to expect to rank well for pages where you&#8217;re not providing an experience dramatically better than everyone else in the top 20 results &#8211; that includes unique descriptions (although that&#8217;s the most basic of the required elements).</li>
<li>
<h4>How would you go about link building for an e-commerce site?</h4>
<p>I&#8217;ve seen a lot of success from e-commerce stores that are very press-worthy and get the attention of media and blogs. My focus would be on designing an experience, a collection of products, and a style that&#8217;s unique and media-worthy. Some good places to get inspiration are the sites showing off unique ecommerce designs. Check out, for example: <a href="http://www.awwwards.com/20-of-the-very-best-e-commerce-web-sites.html" target="_blank">Awwwards</a>, <a href="http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2010/01/22/35-beautiful-and-effective-ecommerce-websites/" target="_blank">Smashing Magazine</a> and <a href="http://engage.synecoretech.com/marketing-technology-for-growth/bid/177023/10-Awesome-Examples-of-Ecommerce-Sites-Using-Responsive-Web-Design" target="_blank">Synecore</a>.</p>
<p>Once you have that media-worthiness in your design and focus, I&#8217;d seek to produce content that helps show off what makes the site unique. Betabrand, for example, focuses on sharing <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/2/20/5430460/move-fast-and-sew-things-how-betabrand-turns-crazy-ideas-into-real-stuff">how their dress yoga pants can provide comfort</a> in professional settings</li>
<li>
<h4>What are &#8220;local citations&#8221;? Do you think they are important for e-commerce sites that sell to a whole country, several countries, or even worldwide?</h4>
<p>Local citations are generally more geared toward the local listings (those that show up in Google&#8217;s &#8220;maps&#8221; style results). If you&#8217;re marketing nationally or globally and don&#8217;t have physical storefronts, these are less important (though anyone mentioning or talking about you online is a good thing).</li>
<li>
<h4>When an e-commerce website has product pages for products that will never be in stock again, how would you handle them for SEO? Remove the page? Leave the pages up with an Out of Stock message? Redirect the page to other products or something else?</h4>
<p>I like to do one of two things &#8211; either redirect the page using a 301 to the most similar item or the category/subcategory level page above it. Or, I&#8217;d leave the page up with a message that it&#8217;s no longer in stock, but here&#8217;s several items that are good substitutes. In the second case, it really becomes a landing page to drive search traffic that may still exist for the item to places where you can help satisfy those searchers.</p>
<h4></h4>
</li>
<li>
<h4>Do you have any suggestions on how category pages should be handled in relation to duplicate content and thin content?</h4>
<p>Google doesn&#8217;t worry too much about duplicate content on category pages &#8211; they expect that many of the words and photos are going to be similar to what&#8217;s found on product pages. The issue is when you have lots of versions of a single category page with little unique value to searchers. For example, having a category page for women&#8217;s pants is a good idea. Having 28 separate category pages for women&#8217;s pants where the only variations are size and color is probably not a great idea. In faceted navigation scenarios like that, I&#8217;d make the color and size filtered pages use a rel=canonical back to the non-faceted women&#8217;s pants page.</li>
<li>
<h4>What are some tips you can give online merchants looking to hire an SEO firm to handle their e-commerce website?</h4>
<p>I really like this short quiz Ian Lurie of Portent Interactive put together on <a href="http://www.portent.com/blog/seo/how-to-hire-an-seo-company-2012-edition.htm" target="_blank">How to Hire an SEO Company</a>. If you follow those guidelines, you&#8217;ll be in good shape. Just don&#8217;t be afraid to ask dumb questions and to follow up by asking &#8220;why&#8221; and &#8220;how do you know that&#8221; &#8211; SEOs aren&#8217;t following any mystical forms of knowledge and should be able to clearly explain why search engines work the way they do.</li>
<li>
<h4>Can you explain how Moz would help PrestaShop merchants?</h4>
<p>Moz has a ton of free resources to help learn about SEO and web marketing. I&#8217;d suggest checking out our <a href="http://moz.com/beginners-guide-to-seo" target="_blank">Beginner&#8217;s Guide to SEO</a>, our <a href="http://moz.com/learn/seo" target="_blank">Learn</a> page, and <a href="http://moz.com/blog/category/whiteboard-friday" target="_blank">Whiteboard Friday</a>.</p>
<p>As far as our software goes, it&#8217;s great for professional web marketers, so if you&#8217;re deep into the worlds of SEO, social media, and content marketing, definitely check it out. But if you&#8217;re planning to hire a marketer or a consultant, they&#8217;re probably the right folks to determine whether a <a href="http://moz.com/products/pro" target="_blank">Moz subscription</a> is right for you.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/seo-expert-series-rand-fishkin-of-moz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop World Tour: Let’s meet a brick and mortar turned online shop in NYC!</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-lets-meet-a-brick-and-mortar-turned-online-shop-in-nyc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-lets-meet-a-brick-and-mortar-turned-online-shop-in-nyc/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 14:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Quentin Audrain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop World Tour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17681</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The growing US ecommerce market, valued at $289 billion, is one of the largest in the world. With endless technological innovations, it’s easy to see why this market grows at 13%. We&#8217;ve stopped in New York City to learn more &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-lets-meet-a-brick-and-mortar-turned-online-shop-in-nyc/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The growing US ecommerce market, valued at $289 billion, is one of the largest in the world. With endless technological innovations, it’s easy to see why this market grows at 13%. We&#8217;ve stopped in New York City to learn more about the largest retail market in the world.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17685" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/PSWT-NY11.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="284" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17681"></span>Today we’re in Chelsea visiting a local store selling fresh and healthy yogurt. Unlike our previous merchants, John and his wife run a successful brick and mortar store. They recently decided to broaden their reach and by launching their online store, SOHHA. With tons of delicious pictures and a bit of uploading, their online store is live and almost ready for business.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17682" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/PSTWT-NY-1.2.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="305" /></p>
<p>Managing an online store that sells fresh products comes with its own set of challenges. We’re learning how he overcame them and seeing how ecommerce changed the way they do business.</p>
<p>Let’s say “Hi” to John!</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/100317278" frameborder="0" width="500" height="281"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/100317278">PrestaShop World Tour: NYC Soha Yogurt</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/prestashop">PrestaShop</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-lets-meet-a-brick-and-mortar-turned-online-shop-in-nyc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Proven Ways to Increase Customer Satisfaction for Your Online Business</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-proven-ways-to-increase-customer-satisfaction-for-your-online-business/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-proven-ways-to-increase-customer-satisfaction-for-your-online-business/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 15:46:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17627</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Customer satisfaction should be a priority for all ecommerce merchants. After all, Bain &#38; Company is attributed for the statistic, “It costs 6-7 times more to acquire a new customer than to retain an existing one.” However, the lack of &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-proven-ways-to-increase-customer-satisfaction-for-your-online-business/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Customer satisfaction should be a priority for all ecommerce merchants. After all, <a href="http://www.Bain.com" target="_blank">Bain &amp; Company</a> is attributed for the statistic, “It costs 6-7 times more to acquire a new customer than to retain an existing one.” However, the lack of customer complaints does not necessarily mean that customers are satisfied.</p>
<p>Unlike a definitive good or bad, customer satisfaction more resembles a continuum. As <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20130604134550-284615-15-statistics-that-should-change-the-business-world-but-haven-t" target="_blank">1 Financial Training Services</a> shares, “96% of unhappy customers don’t complain. However, 91% of those will simply leave and never come back”. Have we convinced you to improve your customer service? If so, we’re helping you do just that with 7 proven ways to increase customer satisfaction for your online business.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17636" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/7-proven-ways-to-increase-customer-satisfaction.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="284" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17627"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #4c797e;">1. Surprise Customers with Freebies</span></h4>
<p>What is better than a freebie? A surprise freebie of course! Use the element of surprise to win customers over. Great examples for unexpected freebies? Try free shipping upgrades, complimentary samples, waived shipping fees, or even include swag (promotional items) in your packages. The best part about surprise freebies is that they can be implemented at your discretion. Once you run out of samples and swag, you simply stop giving them out. Check out this Tweet from a customer who received <a href="https://twitter.com/resanied/status/402845919109861376" target="_blank">PrestaShop Swag</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17648" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/07/Prestashop-Twitter.png" alt="" width="418" height="541" /></p>
<h4><span style="color: #4c797e;">2. “Under Promise, Over Deliver”</span></h4>
<p>This time-proven motto has served many large companies. What does it mean? Be aware of the promises you make to your customer, then aim to deliver more than what was promised. Why does it work? By following this motto, you consistently meet customer expectations. By repetitively delivering this level of service, you covert buyers into loyal customers. As an added bonus, you’ll save money because it costs less to <a href="http://spoken.typepad.com/.a/6a01157036a7d4970b0133f5309dc1970b-pi" target="_blank">retain customers</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #4c797e;">3. Be Clear and Concise</span></h4>
<p>Avoid confusion by clearly outlining your products and service. An example? Ensure the checkout is clear and easy to use. Each Call to Action (CTA) button should lead customers to the next logical step in completing their purchase. Another example? Have a clear <a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/234921" target="_blank">return policy</a>. Guidelines that are unique to your store should be repeated. Specifically, if you don’t accept returns for products that are opened – specify in the return policy <em>and</em> the product description.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #4c797e;">4. Anticipate Customer Needs</span></h4>
<p>This is one of <a href="http://corporate.ritzcarlton.com/en/About/GoldStandards.htm" target="_blank">Ritz Carlton’s</a> 3 steps in achieving the Gold Standard in customer service. It requires a deep and intimate understanding of your customers’ needs. Before a customer can think to raise a concern, address the issue. If someone is purchasing a gift, anticipate your customers’ needs by offering to send a packing list without prices. Addressing concerns before they become a concern keeps a customer happy because they were never unhappy to begin with.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #4c797e;">5. Empathize and be Sincere</span></h4>
<p>The late Maya Angelou once said, “[P]eople will forget what you said, people will forget what you did, but people will never forget how you made them feel.” The best way to get customers to remember the way you made them feel is to provide customer service fueled with empathy and sincerity. Unfortunately, there is no set formula for achieving this. There are however, <a href="http://www.netpromotersystemblog.com/2014/02/24/intelligent-acts-of-kindness-why-it-pays-to-be-nice/" target="_blank">great examples of customer service done right</a>.</p>
<p>My favorite story tells how a, “desk clerk … delivered a pot of tea, gratis and unasked, to the room of a guest with a bad cold.” The customer probably can’t recall whether she had mint or honey tea, nor the desk clerk’s name. However, she will always remember the way she felt upon receiving that welcomed pot of hot tea. The sincerity behind the act is what made it stand out.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #4c797e;">6. Shorten Response Times</span></h4>
<p>In the age of social media, customers expect shorter response times. It may seem impossible to keep up if you are a one-man team. However, there are a few tips to quickly and efficiently address customer concerns. Start by creating customer service email templates. Here’s a sample:</p>
<blockquote><p>Dear {Customer Name},</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We received your email in regards to {summary of their issue}. {If needed, sincerely apologize.} We will gladly resolve your {type of issue} issue by {what you’ll do or provide}. (If you are doing nothing, you must clearly state that. Be sure to provide a reason why.) Please {customers’ next step}.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thank you for being a {positive adjective} customer. If you have any questions or concerns, please feel free to contact me at {contact information} with reference # {order number} as the subject line, or simply reply to this email.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Best regards,</p>
<p>{Name}<br />
{Customer Service information}</p></blockquote>
<p>For issues that arise frequently, create specific emails templates for that issue. Also shorten response times by leveraging <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-social-media-to-improve-customer-service-online-store/" target="_blank">social media as a customer service channel</a>. Monitor your social media accounts for comments and questions. Address them daily by quickly answering their question, sending them to a page with the answer, or providing the email address for customer service.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #4c797e;">7. Show Customers you Care</span></h4>
<p>As you update your site, convey the benefits of each change to customers. This is especially helpful for changes that may seem like a disadvantage for customers. Take for example, <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/matthewzeitlin/netflix-raises-prices-for-new-customers-current-customers-ke" target="_blank">Netflix</a>, an American video streaming company who increased the price of their monthly subscription. They sent emails that:</p>
<ol>
<li>thanked customers for using their service</li>
<li>provided value to customers by extending the current customer rate for 2 years.</li>
</ol>
<p>Although the price increase is a still disadvantage for the customer, Netflix presented the issue in a positive light for customers. Netflix easily showed their customers they care by writing this email.</p>
<p>Are you doing your part in keeping customers satisfied? What works best? Share your methods in the comments below. If you don’t already have a method in place, which of these prevailing ways will you implement in your online store?</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
</div>
<p>Not an online merchant yet? Check out PrestaShop by <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">testing our demo</a> or build your online store today with the best open source ecommerce software by <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">downloading</a> PrestaShop.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-proven-ways-to-increase-customer-satisfaction-for-your-online-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing the User Club: Building PrestaShop together!</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/introducing-the-user-club-building-prestashop-together/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/introducing-the-user-club-building-prestashop-together/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 09:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Quentin Audrain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17609</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Open source is our philosophy and there are many ways you can contribute to PrestaShop: Forums, Forge, GitHub, Crowdin&#8230; Now, you can get more deeply involved: Introducing the User Club. The User Club is designed so that you give direct &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/introducing-the-user-club-building-prestashop-together/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Open source is our philosophy and there are many ways you can contribute to PrestaShop: <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/forums/" target="_blank">Forums</a>, <a href="http://forge.prestashop.com/secure/Dashboard.jspa" target="_blank">Forge</a>, <a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop" target="_blank">GitHub</a>, <a href="https://crowdin.net/project/prestashop-official" target="_blank">Crowdin</a>&#8230;</p>
<p>Now, <strong>you can get more deeply involved</strong>: Introducing the User Club.</p>
<p>The User Club is designed so that you give direct feedback on what we’re working on, what you need and what you’d like to see. <strong>From user experience to important features to merchant habits&#8230; we want to hear your point of view</strong>!</p>
<p>By joining the Club, each month you’ll be asked for your opinion on the upcoming releases.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16534" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/fr/files/2014/07/userclub.png" alt="" width="552" height="361" /></p>
<p> <span id="more-17609"></span>It is a way for us to improve, develop and design the future versions of PrestaShop you&#8217;ll be using every day. It’s how we ensure that the software evolves based on r<strong>eal experiences from real people</strong>.</p>
<p>Here are some examples of what we could ask you:</p>
<p>- Your opinion about several mockups for a page redesign.<br />
- A selection among features you would like to see included in the next release<br />
- Explain how you use a feature and how you would improve it<br />
- and more!</p>
<p><strong>The User Club is open to everyone&#8230; Merchants, Developers and Agencies from all over the world, join us</strong>!</p>
<p>&gt; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/club/" target="_blank">Get involved</a> &lt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/introducing-the-user-club-building-prestashop-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Pieces of Advice from Successful Internet CEOs for Ecommerce Entrepreneurs</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-pieces-of-advice-from-successful-internet-ceos-for-ecommerce-entrepreneurs/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-pieces-of-advice-from-successful-internet-ceos-for-ecommerce-entrepreneurs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 14:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17583</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[CEOs are the driving force of a company, natural leaders dedicated to their company’s success. They determine their team’s direction and continuously grow the company. We&#8217;ve reached out to CEOs in the PrestaShop community and asked them to share some &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-pieces-of-advice-from-successful-internet-ceos-for-ecommerce-entrepreneurs/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>CEOs are the driving force of a company, natural leaders dedicated to their company’s success. They determine their team’s direction and continuously grow the company. We&#8217;ve reached out to CEOs in the PrestaShop community and asked them to share some wisdom for ecommerce entrepreneurs. Although they come from different countries, professional backgrounds and lead different companies, they all gave great advice. We&#8217;ve compiled the best and today we’re sharing 7 pieces of advice from successful Internet CEOs for ecommerce entrepreneurs.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17584" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/BP.img-Internet-CEO.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="225" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17583"></span><span style="color: #000000"><strong>Oleg Cherevatyy</strong> CEO of</span> <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/management/cart2cart" target="_blank">Cart2Cart</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center">“Multichannel is the way eCommerce should work in the 21st century. Get yourself on every possible platform starting from a web store and eBay up to Google Shopping and Facebook. But don’t even think about doing this manually &#8211; automate all the things.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="color: #000000"><strong>Scott McFarlane</strong> CEO of</span> <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/management/avalara" target="_blank">Avalara</a></p>
<blockquote><p>“Your overall strategy is important, but so is compliance. Automating your sales and tax can help you stay focused on your primary expertise.”</p></blockquote>
<p><span style="color: #000000"><strong>Bryan Muthig</strong> CEO of</span> <a href="https://partners.a2hosting.com/solutions.php?id=3682&#038;url=311" target="_blank">A2Hosting</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center">&#8220;Your speed is your success &#8211; first and foremost pick a fast, reliable host. The speed at which your site loads has a significant impact on your conversion rate, slower sites lead to fewer conversions. Also be sure you are utilizing all of the optimization options built into PrestaShop &#8211; they make a big difference.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="color: #000000"><strong>Serge Savchyshyn</strong> CEO &amp; Founder of</span> <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/management/emagicone" target="_blank">eMagicOne</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center">&#8220;If you need to do the task once, simply do it. If you need to do it twice, deal with it. If you have to do it three times, automate it!&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="color: #000000"><strong>Tomer Tagrin</strong> CEO of</span> <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/marketing-visibility/yotpo-social-reviews" target="_blank">Yotpo</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center">“Compared to new visitors, return shoppers cost less to get back into your store and will spend more money. […] Turn these shoppers into your evangelists&#8211;it will significantly increase your bottom line.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="color: #000000"><strong>Erwin van Kralingen</strong> CEO and Founder of</span> <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/marketing-visibility/giveit" target="_blank">Give.it</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center">&#8220;Listen to your customers. And talk back.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="color: #000000"><strong>Ralph Dangelmaier</strong> CEO of</span> <a href="http://go.bluesnap.com/partner-referral/prestashop/" target="_blank">BlueSnap </a></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center">&#8220;E-commerce is currently only 6% of total commerce and only a quarter of e-commerce merchants are set up to sell internationally. The opportunity to sell globally is huge for retailers.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What lessons will you take away from these Internet CEOs? Now that you’re feeling inspired, <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">build your online store</a> with the PrestaShop ecommerce software. Not quite sure? Check out our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">live Demo</a> to test it out.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-pieces-of-advice-from-successful-internet-ceos-for-ecommerce-entrepreneurs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop 1.6.0.7 is Now Available to Update</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-6-0-7-is-now-available-to-update/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-6-0-7-is-now-available-to-update/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 17:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Benjamin Utterback</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello PrestaShop Community! The latest update to 1.6 is here! 1.6.0.7 is now released with more awesomeness. We didn’t forget to squash some bugs and clean up. Here are the main improvements in this update. &#160; Improved cart summary and &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-6-0-7-is-now-available-to-update/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img style="border: 0pt none; float: left; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/02/prestashop_1-6.png" alt="" />Hello PrestaShop Community!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download"><strong>The latest update to 1.6 is here!</strong></a> 1.6.0.7 is now released with more awesomeness. We didn’t forget to squash some bugs and clean up.</p>
<p>Here are the main improvements in this update.</p>
<p><span id="more-17560"></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Improved cart summary and management with several pages + responsiveness</li>
<li>One Page Checkout fixes issue with customer messages</li>
<li>You can now add more than 8 images for a product!</li>
<li>For added security, a warning highlights the installation of a module that is not certified by Addons</li>
<li>Better Cache management throughout the Back and Front Office</li>
<li>We optimized the Dashboard for even stronger accuracy for visitors and orders</li>
<li>Now, all variations are imported when a new theme is added</li>
<li>Better CMS management with bullet points.</li>
<li>Shipping and Carrier fixes for overlapping ranges</li>
<li>Better Product OnBoarding – Theme, Shipping, and Payment pages</li>
<li>Fix of the reduction display for a pre-tax group</li>
<li>Drag &amp; Drop fix for attributes’ order</li>
<li>Fix of new supplier creation form</li>
<li>All the contact details entered in the BO are now correctly displayed in the FO, under Contact details and stores</li>
</ul>
<p>You can <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/developers-versions/changelog/1.6.0.7">view the entire Changelog here</a>.</p>
<p>You know we love your feedback. If you have an issue, we want to know about it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Found a bug or issues?  <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/forums/">– Search it on the Forum</a> and <a href="forge.prestashop.com">Report it to the Forge</a></li>
<li>You know how to fix an issue? - <a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop/">Submit the fix to GitHub</a></li>
<li>Found a wrong translation? - <a href="https://crowdin.net/project/prestashop-official">Fix it on Crowdin</a></li>
</ul>
<p>We would like to thank everybody who helped us with this update. The PrestaShop community is simply great, the best! Nearly 200 bugs and issues were fixed with your help, making this version the strongest PrestaShop yet! Be sure to always <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/set-up-a-test-server-for-your-online-store/">backup and test your upgrades</a> before upgrading your live store.</p>
<p>That’s it for now, <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download">download PrestaShop 1.6 today</a>! Stay tuned for some more exciting news coming soon!</p>
<p>UPDATE: PrestaShop 1.6.0.8 was released on 6/20/2014 with various template and image fixes.</p>
<p>Happy Selling!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-6-0-7-is-now-available-to-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce Success Story – An up close look at WishTrend’s tripling growth</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-success-story-an-up-close-look-at-wishtrends-tripling-growth/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-success-story-an-up-close-look-at-wishtrends-tripling-growth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 14:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17495</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WishTrend is a Seoul based PrestaShop store and an international retailer for Korean beauty products. In a country brimming with cosmetics, only a few major brands ever gain global exposure. Eddie and Ryan, cofounders of this online store, aimed to &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-success-story-an-up-close-look-at-wishtrends-tripling-growth/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://bit.ly/WishTrend" target="_blank">WishTrend</a> is a Seoul based PrestaShop store and an international retailer for Korean beauty products. In a country brimming with cosmetics, only a few major brands ever gain global exposure. Eddie and Ryan, cofounders of this online store, aimed to share “Real Korean Beauty [products]” with the world. Since launching in late 2011, they shipped more than 60% of their 700+ products to international customers in the United States, Canada and Australia.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17497" style="color: #333333; font-style: normal; line-height: 24.375px; margin-top: 0.4em;" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/wish-trend-main.png" alt="" width="580" height="250" /></p>
<p>In 3 short years, this online store has successfully given 50+ local Korean beauty manufacturers international exposure. More impressively, they’ve maintained their tripling growth. Check out their success story and get inspired for yours!</p>
<p><span id="more-17495"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">Why did you choose to open an online store?</span></h4>
<p>Korea has countless cosmetics brands with some of the greatest beauty manufacturers. Our goal is to link global consumers with underrepresented manufacturers from Korea’s cosmetics industry. We chose to open an online store because ecommerce is the easiest way to sell globally. We can communicate with our customers no matter where they are in the world. Also, we can easily update inventory and set up localized payment methods.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17499" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/youtube.png" alt="" width="380" height="307" /></p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">After your launch, what strategies did you use to drive traffic?</span></h4>
<p>First, we attempted to drive organic traffic by improving our SEO. With PrestaShop’s built in features, we easily added Meta titles, descriptions and tags then rewrote our URL’s. We then drove traffic with a strong social media presence on Facebook, YouTube, <a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendTwitter" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendPinterest" target="_blank">Pinterest</a>, and our “WishTrend Glam” blog. The most effective platforms are<a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendFacebook" target="_blank"> Facebook</a> (with over 61,000 likes), <a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendYoutube" target="_blank">YouTube</a> (with over 35,000 subscribers and 1 million views) and our blog, <a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendBlog" target="_blank">WishTrend Glam.</a> They all work together to increase qualified traffic to our website.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17496" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/REVIEWS.png" alt="" width="445" height="217" /></p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">Once customers land on your site, how did you convert them?</span></h4>
<p>We offer customers incentives to make purchases such as free shipping or $5 gift certificates. We then reassure visitors by displaying customer written product reviews on the home page. By leveraging both strategies, we quickly converted visitors into customers.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">What about customer retention &#8211; how did you keep customers coming back?</span></h4>
<p>We send weekly newsletters to our members. In addition, we try to send customized messages to customers based on their purchase history, location and age group to provide personalized product suggestions. This extra effort helps us convert customers again and again.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17498" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/YOTPO-REVIEWS.png" alt="" width="524" height="318" /></p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">Do you use PrestaShop Modules? Which would you recommend?</span></h4>
<p>We currently use the basic <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/social-commerce-facebook-prestashop-modules/7366-yotpo-social-reviews.html" target="_blank">Yotpo module </a>for product reviews. With this module, customers receive an email 15 days after making a purchase asking them to leave a review for products in their order. As an incentive, customers are offered a discount coupon for a future order. We highly recommend this module to other PrestaShop merchants.</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
</div>
<p>Interested in running your own online store? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download</a> PrestaShop today or try our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">demo</a> to experience the PrestaShop software. Take the first step to becoming the next PrestaShop ecommerce success story!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-success-story-an-up-close-look-at-wishtrends-tripling-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Selling on Marketplaces: how to centralize your ecommerce inventory</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-on-marketplaces-how-to-centralize-your-ecommerce-inventory/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-on-marketplaces-how-to-centralize-your-ecommerce-inventory/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 10:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Deborah Penna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17528</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this day and age, selling on e-marketplaces has become relatively indispensable for small to large ecommerce business owners. Building an online presence on European platforms such as eBay, Amazon, Rakuten, Zalando or la Redoute, just to name a few, &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-on-marketplaces-how-to-centralize-your-ecommerce-inventory/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this day and age, selling on e-marketplaces has become relatively indispensable for small to large ecommerce business owners.</p>
<p>Building an online presence on European platforms such as eBay, Amazon, Rakuten, Zalando or la Redoute, just to name a few, can really <strong>give your business the boost it needs to grow</strong> and gain exposure to a large number of potential buyers.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17531" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/Image7.jpg" alt="" width="520" height="289" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17528"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #3366ff">Why sell on marketplaces</span></h2>
<p>The most obvious reason for choosing to sell on marketplaces is that every month, these websites <strong>attract millions of online shoppers</strong> &#8211; realistically speaking, a lot more than you will ever attract to your website. In 2013, Amazon reported <strong>237 million active buyers</strong> worldwide.</p>
<p>Therefore, it makes perfect sense to <strong>link your online store to key marketplaces</strong> and start <strong>reaping the benefits</strong>, which include:</p>
<p>- making your product available to customers in different demographics &#8211; <strong>international    exposure</strong><br />
- <strong>increased level of trust by the buyer</strong>, who is familiar with the marketplace and feels  safe<br />
- security and <strong>fraud protection</strong> offered by the major e-marketplaces<br />
- <strong>marketing benefits</strong>: eBay and Amazon spend millions in driving new customers to their  websites, as mentioned by <a href="http://www.is4profit.com/get-britain-growing/trading-online/how-to-sell-successfully-on-ebay.html" target="_blank">is4profit.</a></p>
<p>Emarketplaces charge a fee to be able to use their services. However, when calculating the cost of acquiring a new customer versus paying a marketplace fee &#8211; it is worth the investment. Learn how to calculate your <a href="http://blog.hubspot.com/ecommerce/calculating-ecommerce-cost-of-customer-acquisition" target="_blank">Cost of Customer Acquisition/ CoCA here</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #3366ff">How to centralize your inventory</span></h2>
<p>If you have decided to sell or are already selling on multiple platforms, <strong>it is fundamental to have a system that will help you easily manage the availability of stock</strong> and gain visibility, across all channels. If, for example, a product sells out on eBay, as a store owner you should know &#8211; in real time &#8211; whether or not, that same product might be available on an another channel. Synchronisation of your inventory levels and order fulfillment, therefore, plays a major role.</p>
<p>Simply by installing a centralised system that will let you list, synchronise and distribute your stock across the various platforms, will allow you to streamline your operations, improve your overall inventory management and handle your entire sales cycle more effectively. One system to manage it all.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17530 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/Marketplaces-image.jpg" alt="" width="619" height="245" /></p>
<h3><span style="color: #3366ff">Neteven &#8211; European Marketplace Management</span></h3>
<p>With over 8 years’ experience in working closely with the major marketplaces in Europe, Neteven has become the leading provider of Marketplace Management solutions.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17529 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/logo-neteven.jpg" alt="" width="215" height="80" /></p>
<p>In order to make it simple for you to sell more efficiently, and <strong>distribute your catalogue across the major European platforms at a click of a mouse</strong>, a marketplace management module has been developed for PrestaShop users.</p>
<p>The module includes the following functionalities:</p>
<p>- Inventory management<br />
- Attributes and variations management<br />
- Bar codes publishing<br />
- Rich media product creation<br />
- Automated listing<br />
- Stock automation<br />
- Repricing<br />
- Optimization tools<br />
- End of transactions<br />
- Reporting tool</p>
<p>Synchronise your PrestaShop catalogue with Neteven and manage all your inventory from a single interface.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/marketplace-prestashop-modules/8091-neteven.html">Neteven module</a> is native in the software and it’s compatible with v.1.4.01 &#8211; v1.6.0.6. It is also available for download, free of charge, on <strong>PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-on-marketplaces-how-to-centralize-your-ecommerce-inventory/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced
Object Caching 831/978 objects using disk: basic

Served from: www.prestashop.com @ 2014-07-15 13:56:02 -->